# **ALVIN JUDE**

nationality Malaysian email alvin@dartarrow.net
d.o.b. 9 March 1984 website http://dartarrow.net
residence Waco, TX phone (254) 413 1023

## ABOUT

As a former DevOps, I enjoy working on the whole stack. My primary research interest lies is in the human factors of computer science; my masters thesis will be in the area of Human Computer Interaction, specifically involving accessibility with gestures. My goal is to make interaction easier at all levels, including the developer level. I strive to increase my breadth of knowledge, to allow me better understanding of the utilization of technology from both consumer and business perspective, while actively maintaining my deep technical roots.

I prefer the trees but I see the forest.

## **EDUCATION**

Masters of Computer Science

2012–Present · Baylor University

Research Area: Human Computer Interaction

Bachelor of Computer Science

2002–2005 · Coventry University

RANK: Honours, Second Class Upper

THESIS: Remote PC Manipulation via PDA over Bluetooth

## **PUBLICATIONS**

Alvin Jude, G. Michael Poor, and Darren Guinness. 2014. *Personal Space: User Defined Gesture Space for GUI Interaction*. In CHI '14 Extended Abstracts on Human Factors in Computing Systems (CHI EA '14). ACM, New York, NY, USA, 1615-1620. DOI=10.1145/2559206.2581242 http://doi.acm.org/10.1145/2559206.2581242

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Basic R · Matlab · C# · Tomcat · HBase · JQuery · Css3 · HAProxy · Heartbeat · DRBD

Intermediate Python · LATEX · C · PostgreSQL · Nmap · Git · Hibernate · Objective-C · Memcached

 $Advanced \qquad \text{NGinX} \cdot \text{Puppet} \cdot \text{Nagios} \cdot \text{Collectd} \cdot \text{PHP}_5 \cdot \text{MySQL} \cdot \text{Java} \cdot \text{Symfony} \cdot \text{OpenVZ}$ 

## NON-TECHNICAL SKILLS

Communication Former Malaysian Public Speaking Champion

Entrepreneurship Baylor NewVenture 2014: Top-5 Finalist & 3rd place Elevator Pitch

Languages English · Native

Malay · Intermediate

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

Baylor University

2013–Present · Research Assistant

Tasked to setup newly formed Human Computer Interaction lab. Mentored juniors, established engineering procedures and infrastructure. Performed research in Hand-Gestural interaction and explored research options with other next-generation devices. Reference: G. Michael Poor · michael poor@baylor.edu

2012–2013 · Teaching Assistant On top of general TA duties, also introduced

fixes and developer's manual to software used in-house for teaching databases.

Reference: Greg Speegle · greg\_speegle@baylor.edu

Self Employed

2010–2012 · Technical Consultant

Served as an independent consultant for various project and companies including the following:

2011–2012 · iOS Development, AGILE PERSPECTIVES — MALAYSIA

Developed iOS applications for an international insurance corporation, as well as one iOS app for a consumer-facing startup dealing in retail. Role included feasibility studies, technical consultation and R&D

2010–2011 · System Administrator, CouchSurfing.org

Daily operations: monitoring, security, optimization, deployment, etc. Tools of the trade included Puppet, Zabbix, HAProxy. Deployed a cluster of static content servers (NGinX) to reduce the load off the dynamic servers which resulted in much higher reliability.

Aflexi

2009–2010 · System Engineer

Aflexi was a CDN Software startup, and is currently a division of OnApp. Responsibilities were more DevOps involving backend development and system administration. Accomplishmenst include building a monitoring infrastructure from the ground up (traditionally done with Nagios) with custom scripts running on a specialized Collectd infrastructurep; used to feed PowerDNS for DNS-based CDN routing. Tools of the trade also included Puppet, Zabbix, Nagios, Reprepro, RRD.

Reference: Whei Wong · whei.wong@onapp.com

iMocha Consulting 2007–2010 · Team Lead

Initially hired as a Junior Java Developer, but quickly tasked to build and run a LAMP team of up to 8 people, dealing mostly with financial institutions. Responsibilities included hiring, firing, and mentoring programmers, system administrators, system analysts, and interns, as well as requirements gathering from clients.

Reference: Koh Kok Wei kokwei@imocha.com.my

Sony Manufacturing 2005–2007 · Engineer, Sony EMCS — Malaysia

Developed Linux-based software required for manufacturing. Developed a tool used to trace products which helped cut down tracability time from 2 working days to about 4 hours. Tools of the trade included MFC, VB.NET, PHP, Postgres, GTK.